Cameron Cooper

☑ cameron.w.cooper@gmail.com ☐ 7199008036 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/cameronwc 🛥 https://cameroncooper.co

SUMMARY

Results focused Security Engineer with:

5 years experience conducting security reviews, administering security tools, and hacking.

4 years experience developing full stack web applications

2 years architecting cloud applications and ETL pipelines

In my most recent position I worked as a Senior Security Engineer leading the Aetna Health DevSecOps team where I supported over 3000 engineers and maintained security for all CVS Health/Aetna Health products.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Security Engineer CVS Health/Aetna Health

September 2020 - Present, Denver, CO

- · Lead Security Engineer for Aetna Health DevSecOps.
- · Created integrations, maintained, and administrated: Datatheorem, OWASP Zap, Checkmarx CxSAST, Prisma Cloud Compute (Twistlock), NexusIQ, and Snyk.
- · Built a system for all security tools to be easily configured and managed under a single React application hosted in AWS infrastructure.
- · Facilitated Security reviews, False Positive reviews, and remediation of security issues.
- · Created and maintained secure by default docker images for use downstream in applications.
- · Created security automation microservices in Python, NodeJS, Bash, and AWS. Utilizing EC2, ECS, ECR, Route53, API Gateway, IAM, S3, VPC, and lambdas.
- · Guided over 3000 engineers on Docker, Python, Security, CI/CD, Secure Architecture, Reviews, and Audits.
- · Built, debugged, maintained, and improved CI pipelines/CircleCI orbs in Jenkins and Circleci.
- Built and integrated a SIEM (ELK stack) into CVS infrastructure.
- Facilitated technical interviews for DevSecOps engineers and Software Security Analysts.
- · Collaborated with Governance, Risk, and Management (GRC) to define, implement, and remain in compliance with security controls including controls governed by HIPPA and PCI-DSS.
- · Led procurement, testing, and integration of new security suites.
- · Created a operational analyst team to streamline the security vulnerability management program. Included documentation, hiring, and training.

DevSecOps Engineer Aetna Health

May 2020 - September 2020, Denver, CO

- · Facilitated Security Reviews, False Positive Reviews, and remediation of security issues.
- · Created and maintained secure by default docker images for use downstream in applications.
- · Created security automation microservices in Python, NodeJS, and bash.
- · Held brown bags on docker, python, security, CI/CD, reviews, and audits.
- · Built, maintained, and improved CI pipelines/CircleCI orbs in Jenkins and Circleci.

Full Stack Software Engineer

Parsons

March 2019 - January 2020, Colorado Springs, CO

- · Worked with a clearance on microservices and ETL pipelines for multiple sects of the military.
- · Created scalable object recognition microservices for images and videos with Darknet and YOLO.
- · Wrote/tested RESTful services with Java and Spring.
- Updated and improved AngularJS front-end applications.
- · Scanned and remediated vulnerabilities in our applications with Fortify Static Code Analysis (SAST).
- · Developed an automated test suite with Postman/Newman.
- · Designed Cloud Data Enrichment pipelines.
- Transformed Natural Language Processing, Data Enrichment, and Import/Export pipelines to production code.

Founder / Software Engineer

Formulated, LLC

January 2017 - Present, Denver, CO

- · Improved client lead generation conversion rate by 79% that improved revenue by \$300k
- · Created Full Stack Web Applications for small businesses that converted leads into customers
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Contracted by companies to do security reviews, penetration testing, and audits
- · Created maintainable and scalable CI/CD pipelines for timely and secure updates

PROJECTS

Home Server

2019 - Present

- · Manage a 30TB Unraid virtualization server/NAS/docker registry for over 40 users.
- · Services include: Bitwarden, Nextcloud, Home Assistant, daily offsite backups to Backblaze, reverse proxy, status pages, game servers, over 30+ docker images.
- · Maintained under the coop.ninja domain.
- · 99.9% Uptime.

FOSS Photography

2019 - Present

- FOSS Photography is a simple open source image aggregator for use in design.
- · Created after I found issues with sourcing royalty free high quality images to use as placeholders or in my final designs.
- · Technologies: ReactJS, Github Actions, Heroku, Snyk.

Deauthentication Detector

2019 - 2019

- · Worked with a peer to create a deauthentication packet detection device.
- · Using a Raspberry pi this device detects a deauthentication packet sent across a network and attempts to find information on the source.
- · Coded with Python3, Node, MongoDB, Bash and Aircrack-ng.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Ethical Hacker

EC-Council · In Progress

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS · 2021

Modern React with Redux Bootcamp

Udemy • 2018

Advanced Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy • 2018

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy • 2017

AngularJS & NodeJS Bootcamp

Udemy • 2018

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Science in Computer Security

University of Colorado Colorado Springs · Colorado Springs, CO · 2019

SKILLS

SAST: Checkmarx, Fortify, Github Advanced Security Suite

DAST: OWASP Zap/Data Theorem

SCA: Snyk/Nexus IQ/Github Advanced Security Suite

Container Security: Twistlock

CI/CD: CircleCI, Jenkins, Github Actions

Container: Docker, Docker-Compose

AWS: Elastic Beanstalk, Secret Manager, EC2, ECR, ECS, VPC, Lambda, IAM, dynamoDB, s3, RDS, VPC, Route 53

Terraform

Python: openCV, Django, Flask

Ruby: Ruby on Rails

Java: Spring
NodeJS: React

Databases: MySQL, PostgresQL, MariaDB, MongoDB